Swastik Nath

Kolkata, West Bengal, India



swastiknath@outlook.com



7872171128



linkedin.com/in/nathswastik

Summary

"Committed to code applications to enhance millions of lives worldwide"

Before proceeding further about me, I would love myself to be introduced as a devotee to all things modern technology. I believe in constant learning and spontaneous absorption of technical skills. Throughout all these years I've grasped more than 14 programming languages and counting, more than 5 database system and counting. I am greatly endeavoured to get to know about the Deep Reinforcement Learning and Machine Learning models, in which I am currently working on. I think, these areas are the most important things modern technology has ever produced.

In the field of programming and computer sciences I have learnt that, there should be no fear in the mind of breaking features in order to test and innovate newer features. So, this game of creating and breaking things that I create is what keeps me going forward in this ever-changing world of computing.

When I first started learning about developing accelerated hardware based applications, at first I thought it would be quite difficult to achieve, because these programs are going to be computationally complex and resource hungry as well. But, I keep my calm and learnt the full development process and become an expert.

I recently started a new software research institute under my company, PositionX Research Division, where I, along with my fellow other collaborators research on different advanced application development techniques. Such as, at the lab, I am currently working on a Cloud-Only Operating System based on Services, which we call, CO-OsBS, which I am sure in future will be able to run on applications without having to install them, eventually replacing physical memory modules.

Experience



Subject Matter Expert, Reinforcement Learning and Advanced Al

White Panda

Dec 2019 - Present (10 months +)



Founder and Engineering Lead

PositionX Machines Research

Sep 2019 - Present (1 year 1 month +)



Certified Partner and Specialist in Watson AI

Aug 2018 - Present (2 years 2 months +)



Senior Software Engineer

Microsoft

May 2017 - Jun 2019 (2 years 2 months)

Education

U Udacity

Deep Reinforcement Learning Nanodegree, Artificial Intelligence 2020 - 2020

- 1. I mastered the fundamentals of reinforcement learning by writing my own implementations of many classical solution methods.
- 2. I applied deep learning architectures to reinforcement learning tasks. I trained my own agents that navigates a virtual world from sensory data using Unity ML Agents.
- 3. I learnt the theory behind evolutionary algorithms and policy-gradient methods. I also designed my own algorithm to train a simulated robotic arm to reach target locations.
- 4. I learnt how to apply reinforcement learning methods to applications that involve multiple, interacting agents. These techniques are used in a variety of applications, such as the coordination of autonomous vehicles.

Udacity

Machine Learning Engineer Nanodegree, Machine Learning 2020 - 2020

- Build a Python Package: I Wrote a Python package on my own using software engineering best practices for writing production level code. This project was optional and was not be graded.
- Deploy a Sentiment Analysis Model: Using SageMaker, deployed my own PyTorch sentiment analysis model, which is trained to recognize the sentiment of movie reviews (positive or negative).
- Plagiarism Detector: Engineered features that can help identify cases of plagiarism in text and deployed a trained plagiarism detection model using Amazon SageMaker.
- Capstone Project & Proposal: I created a model that can efficiently identify types of pneumonia one has by using the X-Ray data.

Udacity

Data Engineering Nanodegree, Data Engineering and Data Science 2020 - 2020

U Udacity

Intel Edge AI For IOT Developers Nanodegree, Artificial Intelligence and Internet of Things 2020 - 2020

PROJECT 1: DEPLOYING PEOPLE COUNTER: github.com/swastiknath/iot_ud_1 Investigated different pre-trained models for person detection, and detect the number of people in the frame, and the time spent there.

PROJECT 2: DESIGN A SMART QUEUING SYSTEM: github.com/swastiknath/iot_ud_2
Built custom queuing systems for the retail, manufacturing and transportation sectors and used the Intel®
DevCloud for the Edge to test your solutions performance.

PROJECT 3: BUILD A COMPUTER POINTER CONTROLLER: gtihub.com/swastiknath/iot_ud_3 Used models available in the OpenVINO™ toolkit to control computer pointer using eye gaze.



Indian Institute of Technology, Roorkee

Data Engineering With Hadoop and Spark, Big Data Engineering 2019 - 2020

The Electronics & ICT Academy program is sponsored by the Ministry of Electronics and Information Technology, Govt. of India.

The E&ICT Academy IIT Roorkee conducts short courses/FDPs in the emerging areas to enrich & upgrade subject knowledge and technical skills benefiting faculty, working professionals and Govt. employees.

The trained beneficiaries are expected to create a cascading effect, transforming the competencies and standards in the parent institutes/organizations.

Udacity

Computer Vision Nanodegree, Computer Vision, Artificial Intelligence 2020 - 2020

U Udacity

React Nanodegree, Application Development, Desktop, Web and Mobile 2020 - 2020

Licenses & Certifications



Oracle Certified Master, Java EE 6 Enterprise Architect - Oracle

SJK004855S



Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist: .NET Framework 3.5, Windows Communication Fnd Applications (MCTS) - Microsoft

MS-8488-SUD



Certified Android App Developer - Manipal Global Education Services

Roll No: 54928



Python For Applied Data Science - IBM

XG7WBWZ6YDLQ



Machine Learning With Python - IBM

SAEWRFV3VEDP



Databases and SQL for Data Science - IBM

K86HU22S9UBZ



Data Science Methodology - IBM

NJ5WND68AQD2

Data Visualisation with Python - IBM 466KL2HQYC9W Open Source Tools for Data Science - IBM 4Q6E4QJN4ZQJ Data Analysis with Python - IBM 6YTSVD6Q7H9P Applied Data Science Capstone - IBM AC855WS6XHWX **Data Science Orientation - IBM** 6FAX67MRPDD4 G API Design and Fundamentals of Google Cloud's Apigee API Platform by Google Cloud (With Honours) - Google EJZAKK3PGSHM **Data Science Professional Certificate - IBM** G API Development on Google Cloud's Apigee API Platform (with Honors) - Google TJRJF2BZLQC5 G API Security on Google Cloud's Apigee API Platform - Google QUX55VJ3HDL6 Develop APIs with the Apigee API Platform Specialization - Coursera NAX6AVCRZU4K Deep Learning - IBM Object Oriented Java Programming: Data Structures and Beyond - UC San Diego IBM Certified Specialist - Advanced Data Science - IBM ZKVSXGSTP45K

Fundamentals of Scalable Data Science - IBM

UH6RNFVKM5BT

IBM	Advanced Machine Learning and Signal Processing - IB	Μ
	VLTH92YB7U4S	

- Applied AI with DeepLearning IBM 8RJRS7ZYPPDH
- Computer Vision and Image Analysis Microsoft 6c1f7fbc81f749f595157a6c7a555541
- Intoduction to Artificial Intelligence IBM PDLACJRPMHHD
- **Building AI Powered Chatbots with Watson** IBM RKUTJPQE53JR
- Improving Deep Neural Networks: Hyperparameter tuning, Regularization and Optimization - deeplearning.ai 8XXYF9EMCVP6
- Neural Networks and Deep Learning deeplearning.ai EEJA95WJUE9E
- IBM Power Systems Cognitive Foundations IBM db547a62febe4958a9d601e936a7f50b
- Structuring Machine Learning Projects deeplearning.ai PFSVEC5QUQB7
- Convolutional Neural Networks deeplearning.ai UG4KG9J37CBS
- Intermediate C++ Microsoft b45a45c2396a45f0a991637194866f37
- Introduction to C++ Microsoft 06b4672aeae7470e91e84e5fe3b7d12f
- in Android Development Essential Training LinkedIn

- Android Studio Essentials Training LinkedIn
 Ae2U0btSX8WafhjKLDdCtS_DmU_f
- Matlab Onramp Training MathWorks
- Intoduction to Programming with MATLAB Vanderbilt University
- Control of Mobile Robots Georgia Institute of Technology
- Sequence Models deeplearning.ai 23S6FFJ99FL3
- Deep Learning Specialization deeplearning.ai ZEE3DCV5JWXG
- Google Cloud Platform Fundamentals: Core Infrastructure Google 8UVJZZMT8HUH
- **C** End-to-End Machine Learning with TensorFlow on GCP Google JYUVL7PMYGC2
- Introduction to TensorFlow for Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, and Deep Learning - deeplearning.ai
 VP5FN97CHR55
- Convolutional Neural Networks in Tensorflow deeplearning.ai 3FG6262LQMNE
- Natural Language Processing with Tensorflow deeplearning.ai AMUET75VKPFU
- Sequences, Time Series and Prediction deeplearning.ai 552MXLJB5D3E
- TensorFlow in Practice Specialization deeplearning.ai K74AQ76JVFNL

- **Enterprise Design Thinking Practioner** IBM Hadoop Programming - Level 1 - IBM Understanding Android Applications Basic - Pluralsight **REP ID: 4127** Advanced C++ - Microsoft 1fe5b839d23b4c92b0a6550ce8e2137d Parallal Computing with Dask - DataCamp 10404254 Introduction to Machine Learning With Sound - IBM **Enterprise Design Thinking - Team Essentials for AI - IBM** Working With Android Tools and Testing - Pluralsight **REP ID: 4127** Introduction to Matplotlib - DataCamp 10548097 Introduction to Graph Theory - UC San Diego 3EA2YYAJQKG2 **G** How Google Does Machine Learning - Google ZAYM43DC6YVK C Launching into Machine Learning - Google ZDVE2Y2AE8XZ Intro To Tensorflow - Google F5LYS3HY5MHA **G** Feature Engineering - Google
- G Art and Science of Machine Learning Google

UPE8ZX922CCT

YW7PGPA2WKHG

- G Machine Learning With Tensorflow With Google Cloud Platform Specialization Google SDYKQYAJMZAQ
- Introduction to Computer Vision Using Watson and OpenCV IBM PZNLQLS22BMK
- Getting Started with Al using IBM Watson IBM NGXAK2MS2DZE
- Building AI Applications with Watson APIs IBM WCGJMWG28842
- Applied AI Professional Certificate IBM BC4AZS9UWPZ7
- Master The Mainframe 2019 Part-3 Real World Challenge IBM
- Master the Mainframe 2019 Part-2 IBM
- IBM MQ Developer Essentials IBM
- G Architecting Hybrid Cloud Infrastructure with Anthos Google HZQGHBAYUQPB
- Flutter 2020 Bootcamp The App Brewery
- Functions, Methods and Interfaces in Go University of California, Irvine Division of Continuing Education
 4GZF9HTYL228

Skills

Java Developer • Android Developer • Machine Learning Expert • Software Development • Windows software development • Custom Software Development • Python Developer • Web-based Software Development • Software Development Methodologies • Blockchain